Guide to the Joseph W. Eaton Papers, 1981-1997 UA.90.F58
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Joseph W. Eaton Papers
1981-1997
1993-1997
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Eaton, Joseph W.
UA.90.F58
2.5 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
Dr. Joseph W. Eaton was appointed professor of social work research at the University of Pittsburgh in January of 1959 and shortly thereafter had a joint appointment to the Graduate School of Public Health. The collections consists almost entirely of documents related to two areas: national identity systems and the cable television franchise in the City of Pittsburgh.
Biography
Dr. Joseph W. Eaton was appointed professor of Social Work Research in January at the University of Pittsburgh in 1959 and shortly thereafter had a joint appointment to the Graduate School of Public Health. In 1974 his appointment moved to the Graduate School of Public and International Affairs where he remained until his retirement on December 31, 1989. Born in Nuremberg, Germany on Sept. 28, 1919, he emigrated to New York in 1934, and married Helen Goodman in 1947. He earned a BS degree from Cornell University in Sociology in 1940 and a Ph.D. from Columbia University in 1948.
Scope and Content Notes
This collection consists primarily of documents concerning Dr. Eaton's research interests in national identity card systems and his work with Cable Television franchising issues in Pittsburgh.
The collection contains correspondence, reports and publications regarding the possible implementation of a national identity card or identification number system that would document the employment eligibility status of immigrants, aliens and citizens. Related issues such as privacy, security, Alien Documentation, Identification and Telecommunication System (ADIT), social security cards, fair labor standards, legal and illegal immigration, Mexican migration, and migrant workers are also documented in this collection.
Dr. Eaton became involved with the issue of cable television rate pricing and cable channel packages in Pittsburgh in the mid 1990's. The collection contains correspondence on the Pittsburgh cable television franchise with Tele-Communications, Inc. (TCI), minutes of the Pittsburgh Cable Communications Advisory Committee (PCCAC), the franchise agreement between the City of Pittsburgh and the local rate order reports and appeals.
Also in the collection are a small number of documents relating to firearms and crime as well as legislation on missing children.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Joseph Eaton on July 14, 1998.
Previous Citation
Joseph W. Eaton Papers, UA.90.F58, University Archives, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Migrant labor -- United States; Missing children -- United States; Telecommunication policy -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; University of Pittsburgh; Cable television -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Immigrants -- United States -- Identification; Identification cards -- Law and legislation -- United States; Federation for American Immigration Reform; Tele-Communications, Inc.; United States. Fair labor standards act of 1938; Eaton, Joseph W.
- Correspondence, 1981-82 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1983-84 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Agendas and minutes Pittsburgh Cable Communications Advisory Committee (PCCAC), October -December 1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Agenda and minutes PCCAC, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Agenda and minutes PCCAC, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence and supporting documentation, Jan-May 1996 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence and supporting documentation, June-Dec. 1996 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Agenda and minutes PCCAC, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Research proposal on national identity databases (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Articles, news releases and brochures (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Articles and reports (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Published and unpublished reports by Bustamente, Torres, North, Piore, Camara and Roberts on immigration (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Franchise agreement between the City of Pittsburgh and Pittsburgh Tele-Communications, Inc. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Document: cable rate approval (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Appeal of local rate order, June 30, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Opposition to appeal of 1997 local rate order, July 14, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Annual reports- TCI, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 20-A)
- Annual reports- PCCAC, 1993-94 (Box 1, Folder 20-B)
- Publications- Paine Webber Presentation from the 25th Annual Media Conference, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 21-A)
- Publications- Keystone Connections, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 21-B)
- Publication: Nilson report, Feb. 1982-Jan.1985 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Publications- Fair Labor Standards Act, Feb. 1980 (Box 1, Folder 23-A)
- Publications- Boe vs Wright; reports by Cornelius, Gordon and Newman on immigration (Box 1, Folder 23-B)
- Reports on employment eligibility and employer responsibility (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Publications: U.S. Immigration and Refugee Policy; reports by Vialet, Masanz and North on immigration (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Reports on identifications systems (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Proposal on Automated Tax Administration System (IRS); reports on privacy and security including Giesecke Derrient (company). (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Publications: Workers Defense League,"Forgery, disinformation and political operations" (STA-501); ISR Newsletter, Oct 1981 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Publications on labor (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Proceedings and reports on Soviet policy, slavery and peonage practices, missing children, and personal documentation (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Joseph Eaton in World War II, 2009